Register of the Jay Lovestone papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- MEMORABILIA, 1909-1976 (Box 688)
  - Scrapbook of clippings of newspaper column by Jay Lovestone entitled "At First Glance," from Workers Age, 1938 October 8 - 1939 October 27
  - Scrapbooks of clippings and leaflets on the American Socialist Party
    Probably compiled by C. E. Ruthenberg.
    - 1909-1910
    - 1910-1911
    - 1912-1914
    - 1915
- DAMAGED MATERIAL (Boxes 689-695)
  Consists of papers removed from the collection because of fragile and poor condition. Photocopies of this material have been filed throughout the collection in the folders from which the originals were withdrawn.
- MAP (Art racks No. 4)
  Original AFL-CIO map of slave labor camps in Russia.
  - Original AFL-CIO Map Of Slave Labor Camps In Russia (Art racks No. 4)
- SOUND RECORDINGS, 1952, undated (Tape cabinet)
  Speeches by Jay Lovestone and Irving Brown.
  - Brown, Irving, "As We See It," speech, undated (Tape cabinet)
    Access
    Use copy reference number: 75091_a_0005861
    Brown describes the labor union movement in Europe.
  - Lovestone, Jay, speech, circa 1952 April 28
    Use copy reference number: 75091_a_0005860
    Lovestone speaks to a labor-friendly crowd about the labor movement. Included in his remarks is how labor relates to the American experience, how it fits into other national experiences, and comments about the Soviet Union.
- PHOTOGRAPHS, circa 1908-1974 (Photo file)
  559 prints, 3 slides, 33 postcards, and 10 negatives depicting Jay Lovestone and others.
  - 12 prints of Jay Lovestone; 1 print of Charles Zimmerman; 5 prints of Jay Lovestone and others; 3 prints of David Dubinsky; 3 prints of Jay Lovestone and Luigi Antonini; 4 prints of Jay Lovestone and David Dubinsky; 3 street scenes; 1 print of Jay Lovestone and others, circa 1910, 1925-1935 (Envelope A)
  - 8 prints at political picnic (5 with Jay Lovestone as speaker); 2 prints of Max Bedacht, Ann Damon, C. E. Ruthenberg, William Z. Foster, and Jay Lovestone; 1 print of Jay Lovestone and Ella Wolfe; 2 prints of a Sacco-Vanzetti Demonstration, circa 1924-1925, 1930 August 22 (Envelope B)
  - 12 prints of Jay Lovestone and others, circa 1932 (Envelope C)
  - 1 print of Workers School (Jay Lovestone, Jack Stachel, William Weinstone, Bertram Wolfe, Herbert Zam, Ben Davidson, Rose Goldberg, Minnie Lurie, and Miriam Zam); 1 print of Jay Lovestone, Bertram Wolfe, and others, circa 1929 (Envelope D)
  - 20 prints of Jay Lovestone; 3 negatives, circa 1925-1935 (Envelope E)
  - 1 print of Jay Lovestone, William Munger, Irving Brown, Bertram Wolfe, and Ben Davidson; 1 print of Jay Lovestone, William Munger, Irving Brown, and Ben Davidson; 1 print of William Munger; 8 prints taken of street scenes in Berlin by Nicholas Dozenberg; 1 print of Ellis Chryssos; 1 print of early Bolshevik leaders in Russia including V. I. Lenin and Iurii Martov, circa 1931, 1936 (Envelope F)
  - 3 prints of Irving Brown, Jay Lovestone, and others; 5 prints of Irving Brown; 1 print of Irving Brown and Guilio Pastore; 1 print of Irving Brown, Michael Ross, J. H. Oldenbroek, Elmer Cope, and George Meany; 1 print of Irving Brown, George Meany, and Arthur Deakin; 2 prints of Irving Brown and others (Envelope G)
  - 3 prints of Jay Lovestone, Harry Goldberg, and Middle Eastern labor leaders; 8 prints of Jay Lovestone and others at the American Institute for Free Labor Development; 3 prints of Jay Lovestone and others, 1962, 1971, 1974 (Envelope H)
  - 3 prints of Jay Lovestone, President and Mrs. Richard M. Nixon, and others; 2 prints of Jay Lovestone and others; 1 print of Jay Lovestone, David Dubinsky, and others; 15 prints of Harry and Rose Goldberg, Mr. and Mrs. George Meany, David Dubinsky, and Italian labor leaders; 5 prints of Harry and Rose Goldberg; 2 prints of Harry Goldberg, 1955 June (Envelope I)
  - 56 prints of and by Elfriede Thiemann (Envelope J)
  - 14 prints of Jay Lovestone; 2 prints of Jay Lovestone and others aboard the Queen Mary; 4 prints of Jay Lovestone and others aboard the Queen Elizabeth; 8 prints of meeting of labor leaders, London (Jay Lovestone, George Meany, Matthew Woll, William Green, David Dubinsky, and others); 1 print of George Meany; 1 print of Jay Lovestone and others, circa 1955, 1960 (Envelope K)
  - 2 prints of Jay Lovestone and others at International Confederation of Trade Unions Congress in Stockholm; 1 print of Averell Harriman and others at ICFTU Congress; 1 print of Jay Lovestone, Averell Harriman, and others; 1 print of Jay Lovestone and others, Tokyo; 6 prints of Jay Lovestone and Ludwig Rosenberg, Berlin; 1 print of Jay Lovestone, Georg Leber, and others, Berlin; 1 print of Jay Lovestone, 1949, 1953 July, 1966, 1968 (Envelope L)
  - 3 prints of Jay Lovestone; 1 print of Jay Lovestone and George Meany; 2 prints of Jay Lovestone, George Meany and Konrad Andenauer, Germany; 2 prints of Ludwig Erhardt; 1 print of Jay Lovestone, Klaus Dohrn, and Pope Pius XII; 1 print of Jay Lovestone, David Dubinsky, and Irving Brown at the Vatican, 1955, 1965, 1966, 1971 (Envelope M)
  - 1 print of Jay Lovestone and George Meany; 1 print of Jay Lovestone, George Meany, and others; 5 prints of Jay Lovestone and others; 1 print of Jay Lovestone, George Meany, Dean Rusk, and others; 1 print of Jay Lovestone, George Meany, and Willy Brandt; 1 print of Jay Lovestone and others, Los Angeles; 1 print of Jay Lovestone, 1963, 1971 (Envelope N)
  - 8 prints of a political gathering with Jay Lovestone, Louis Fraina, Charles Zimmerman, and others; 5 prints of Jay Lovestone and others; 4 prints of Jay Lovestone and John Brophy; 1 print of John Brophy and unidentified man; 2 prints of union meeting, circa 1935 (Envelope O)
  - 10 prints of Jay Lovestone (proofs) (Envelope P)
  - 2 prints of Norman Tallentire; 1 print of Norman Tallentire and others; 9 prints of scenes of Lansing, Michigan, "Labor Holiday;" 1 print of Jay Lovestone and others; 1 print of Jay Lovestone and Norman Thomas, 1937 June 7 (Envelope Q)
  - 4 prints of Tom Mooney; 1 print of Warren Billings; 1 print of Tom Mooney with police; 1 print of Eugene Debs on "Debs for President" train; 3 prints of Tom Mooney on "Debs for President" train, possibly campaign, 1908 (Envelope R)
  - 1 print of Alexandra Kollontai and large gathering (possibly Russian political meeting); 11 prints of Jay Lovestone; 1 print of C. E. Ruthenberg; 1 print of Alexander Bittelman, William Z. Foster, and James P. Cannon, circa 1924-1925 (Envelope S)
  - 9 prints of Esther Mendelssohn; 7 prints of unidentified woman (Envelope T)
  - 4 prints of Jay Lovestone and others; 2 prints of Jay Lovestone and others at United Nations Tunisian reception; 2 pages of proofs of Jay Lovestone and others; 5 prints of Jay Lovestone and others; 2 prints of Jay Lovestone and others at Armed Forces Information School, 1953, 1957 (Envelope U)
  - 3 prints of Phan Quang Dan; 2 prints of Matthew Woll, Jay Lovestone, and others; 1 print of Yerucham Meshel and Jay Lovestone; 2 prints of Jay Lovestone and others; 1 print of Seiji Amaike and George Meany; 4 prints of Jay Lovestone, Willy Brandt, street scene of Berlin, Jay Lovestone addressing crowd in Berlin; 1 print of Jay Lovestone addressing convention breakfast, 1962, 1964, 1969 (Envelope V)
  - 7 prints of Jay Lovestone and others; 1 print of Jay Lovestone and others; 1 print of General George C. Marshall, Chou En-lai, Chu Teh, Chang Chi-chung, Mao Tse-tung, and Lin Tsu-hau; 2 prints of Harry Bridges and others; 1 print of President Franklin D. Roosevelt and others; 1 print and caption of Ghanian prisoners (Envelope W)
  - 9 prints of recipients of CARE packages; 1 print of map of China; 11 prints of scenes in Russia; 9 negatives of scenes in Russia, circa 1946 (Envelope X)
  - 36 prints of Jay Lovestone; 1 print of Dean of Canterbury Hewlett Johnson and Jay Lovestone; 1 print of Hewlett Johnson and others; 1 print of Rafael Carrillo; 1 print of Diego Rivera and others; 11 scenes of Mexico; 1 print of wrecked airplane; 3 prints of Ella Wolfe; 1 print of Jay Lovestone and others, circa 1923 (Envelope Y)
  - 15 unidentified prints; 4 prints of Elsie Ruak and others, Hamburg; 1 print of Natalie Davies; 1 print of Edna Brand Mann; 1 print of Johannes Mihkelson; 2 prints of Jay Lovestone and unidentified man, 1946 (Envelope Z)
  - 34 postcards (Envelope AA)
    1 of Leon Trotsky; 1 of I. T. Smilga; 2 printed by the Communist Party, Zurich; 1 of the home of V. I. Lenin in Zurich; 4 of scenes in Canada; 5 of scenes in Long Island; 1 of a scene in Colorado; 4 of scenes in New Mexico; 1 of scene in Germany, and 14 of scenes in Romania.
  - 16 prints of scenes in Romania (Envelope BB)
  - 3 slides of Jay Lovestone; 1 print of Jay Lovestone; 1 negative of Jay Lovestone; 1 print of unidentified group of people (possibly taken in Moscow of Communist Youth Group) (Envelope CC)
  - 26 prints (possibly Moscow) (Envelope DD)
  - 28 unidentified prints (Envelope EE)
  - 2 prints of Charles Hueber(?), 1929 (Envelope mFF)
  - 1 print of Francis Biddle; 1 print of Lansing, Michigan, "Labor Holiday;" 2 prints of unidentified woman, 1937 June 7, 1942 (Envelope mGG)
  - 1 print of Jan Masaryk (Envelope mHH)
  - 1 print of Nicolai Bukharin (Envelope mII)
  - 1 unidentified print (family portrait) (Envelope mJJ)
  - 1 print of Summer Labor Institute, World Labor Co-Operation, (Jay Lovestone and others), 1938 June 23 (Envelope mKK)
  - 12 prints depicting scenes of daily life in Germany, 1947 (Envelope LL)
  - 2 prints of AFL meeting, 1951 (Envelope MM)
  - 3 prints of Harry and Rose Goldberg at a cultural conference in Bombay, India, also depicting Bombay mayor S. K. Patil, Wystan Hugh Auden, Mr. and Mrs. Burnham, S. R. Mohan Das, Salvador de Madariaga, Julius Margolin, M. R. Masani, Asoka Mehta, Denis de Rougemont, Stephen Spender, and Norman Thomas, 1951, March 28-31 (Envelope NN)
  - 2 prints of Harry and Rose Goldberg at a meeting of the Automobile Workers Union, INTUC, Bombay, India, 1951 April 13 (Envelope OO)
  - 2 prints (and 4 duplicates) of Harry and Rose Goldberg at the headquarters of the P.B.K.A. Workers Trade Union, Bandung, Indonesia, 1951 November 3 (Envelope PP)
  - 5 prints (and 9 duplicates) of Anna Kethly and others, undated (Envelope QQ)
  - Approximately 200 prints, negatives, and postcards, including of Jay Lovestone (unsorted) (Envelope RR-WW)
    See Box 754.
- [Material received after completion of register to Boxes 1-695]
  The Hoover Institution Archives acquired the main body of its Jay Lovestone papers in 1975. However, smaller additions to the collection continued to be received throughout Lovestone's life and, via his estate, after his death in 1990. The Register to the Jay Lovestone papers was completed in 1980 and covers all material received up to that time: Boxes 1-695, plus considerable audiovisual material. That Register remains the principal overall description of the Lovestone papers and should first be consulted by the researcher.
  This Addendum covers the materials in Boxes 696-899, received after completion of the Register. As might be expected, these materials date disproportionately from the later years of Lovestone's life, but they include much earlier material as well. Most of the pre-1980 material represented in the Addendum is certainly unique within the collection. However, because of multiple copies of some items or presence of both originals and photocopies of others, there are undoubtedly some instances of duplication between material in the main part of the papers and that covered by the Addendum. It was not practicable to search systematically for possible duplication of each item in the Addendum materials, and no attempt was made to do so. The researcher is alerted accordingly.
  Other pseudonyms that may appear in this collection include "E. F.," "Ed Five," and "Ed Fisher," all of which are believed to be pseudonyms of Leonid Belsky, and "Y. F.," believed to be a pseudonym of I. E. Ferguson. The pseudonym "Comrade F." appears to depend on context, and may mean either Ferguson or Fraina.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1920-1989 (Boxes 696-712)
  - General
    - 1936 (Folder 696: 1)
    - 1941-1948 (Folder 696: 2)
    - 1950-1959 (Folder 696: 3)
    - 1960-1969 (Folder 696: 4)
    - 1970-1979 (Folder 696: 5)
    - 1980-1989 (Folder 696: 6)
    - 1980s, undated (Folder 696: 7)
  - AFL-CIO, 1956-1987 (Box-folder 697: 1)
  - Abdelali, Abderrahman B., 1955-1964 (Folder 697: 2)
  - Abramovich, Rafail, 1951 (Folder 697: 3)
  - Acheson, Dean, 1960-1961 (Folder 697: 4)
  - Adenauer, Konrad, 1955-1966 (Folder 697: 5)
  - Alexander, Robert J., 1978-1983 (Folder 697: 6)
  - All Pakistan Confederation of Labour, 1952 (Folder 697: 7)
  - Allen, Will, 1945 (Folder 697: 8)
  - Allott, Gordon, 1960 (Folder 697: 9)
  - Amalgamated Union of Engineering Workers, 1973 (Folder 697: 10)
  - American Federation of Labor, 1951-1955 (Folder 697: 11)
  - American Foundation for the Blind, 1967-1982 (Folder 697: 12)
  - American Institute for Free Labor Development, 1973-1978 (Folder 697: 13)
  - Amnesty International, 1978 (Folder 697: 14)
  - Andrews, Richard H., 1962 (Folder 697: 15)
  - Andrews, Sarainne, 1955-1977 (Folder 697: 16)
  - Angleton, James and Cicely, 1978-1988 (Folder 697: 17)
  - Arden House Conference on Science and Labor, 1983 (Folder 697: 18)
  - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 1958 (Folder 697: 19)
  - Army War College, 1952 (Folder 697: 20)
  - Ashton, D. L. W., 1972 (Folder 697: 21)
  - Asian-American Free Labor Institute, 1973-1974 (Folder 697: 22)
  - Atlantic Council, 1972-1989 (Folder 697: 23)
  - Aulnay, Jacques and Sheila d', 1976-1987 (Folder 697: 24)
  - Australian Association for Cultural Freedom, 1969 (Folder 697: 25)
  - Ba Tun, 1961 (Folder 697: 26)
  - Balfour, Natalie, 1984-1988 (Folder 697: 27)
  - Bang-Jensen, Helen, 1959-1960 (Folder 697: 28)
  - Barth, Heinz, 1974-1979 (Folder 697: 29)
  - Barton, Paul, 1969-1973 (Folder 697: 30)
  - Barwald, Helmut F., 1973 (Folder 697: 31)
  - Beichman, Arnold, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 698: 1)
  - Berman, Paul, 1988 (Folder 698: 2)
  - Bernard, Viola W., 1938-1965 (Folder 698: 3)
  - Bill, James A., 1978-1979 (Folder 698: 4)
  - Billick, Anita C., 1981-1988 (Folder 698: 5)
  - Bluestein, Abe, 1976 (Folder 698: 6)
  - Bolcsfoldi, Andor, 1978 (Folder 698: 7)
  - Borochowicz, Elly, 1953-1986 (Folder 698: 8)
  - Borochowicz, Leo, 1952 (Folder 698: 9)
  - Brandel, Kuno, 1963 (Folder 698: 10)
  - Brandt, Willy, 1936-1966 (Folder 698: 11)
  - Brentano, Heinrich von, 1955-1963 (Folder 698: 12)
  - Brewer, Roy M., 1977-1978 (Folder 698: 13)
  - Brod, Mario Emmanuel, 1972 (Folder 698: 14)
  - Brombart, David, 1978-1985 (Folder 698: 15)
  - Brophy, John, 1937 (Folder 698: 16)
  - Brown, George, 1955-1956 (Folder 698: 17)
  - Brown, Irving, 1947-1981 (Folder 698: 18)
  - Brown, William Montgomery, 1930 (Folder 698: 19)
  - Bruce, David, 1952 (Folder 698: 20)
  - Bruegel, John W., 1958-1978 (Folder 698: 21)
  - Bryant, Farris, 1962 (Folder 698: 22)
  - Buckley, William F., 1955 (Folder 698: 23)
  - Bunche, Ralph J., 1967 (Folder 698: 24)
  - Bundy, William P., 1966-1977 (Folder 698: 25)
  - Burke, Arleigh, 1952-1969 (Folder 698: 26)
  - Business Week, 1956 (Folder 698: 27)
  - Caffery, Jefferson, 1948-1951 (Box-folder 699: 1)
  - Callesen, Gerd, 1987 (Folder 699: 2)
  - Carney, Jack, 1952-1955 (Folder 699: 3)
  - Chaikin, Sol C., 1977-1985 (Folder 699: 4)
  - Chakravarty, B. N., 1962 (Folder 699: 5)
  - Chelli, Zouhaier, 1956 (Folder 699: 6)
  - Chen Chih-mai, 1954-1955 (Folder 699: 7)
  - Cherne, Leo, 1961 (Folder 699: 8)
  - Chudnovsky, David and Gregory, 1979-1984 (Folder 699: 9)
  - Ciolkosz, Adam, 1972 (Folder 699: 10)
  - City College of New York, 1961-1989 (Folder 699: 11)
  - Clark, Mark W., 1945-1960 (Folder 699: 12)
  - Clay, Lucius D., 1949-1977 (Folder 699: 13)
  - Cleveland, Harlan, 1982 (Folder 699: 14)
  - Cole, Helen Grady, 1963-1971 (Folder 699: 15)
  - Colson, Charles W., 1970-1972 (Folder 699: 16)
  - Committee for the Free World, 1980-1986 (Folder 699: 17)
  - Committee on the Present Danger, 1976-1988 (Folder 699: 18)
  - Conte, Silvio O., 1960 (Folder 699: 19)
  - Correll, John Franklin, 1974 (Folder 699: 20)
  - Coste, Brutus, 1968-1979 (Folder 699: 21)
  - Council on Foreign Relations
    - 1952-1982 (Folder 699: 22)
    - 1983-1989 (Box-folder 700: 1)
  - Cramer, Ernst, 1976-1978 (Folder 700: 2)
  - Cuito, Amadeo, 1966 (Folder 700: 3)
  - Cuneo, Ernest L., 1955-1986 (Folder 700: 4)
  - Curtis, Thomas B., 1959 (Folder 700: 5)
  - Das, S. R. Mohan, 1958-1980 (Folder 700: 6)
  - Davies, Natalie R., 1947-1951 (Folder 700: 7)
  - Dennen, Leon, 1951 (Folder 700: 8)
  - Deutsche Angestellten-Gewerkschaft, 1960 (Folder 700: 9)
  - Deutscher Gewerkschaftsbund, 1955-1981 (Folder 700: 10)
  - Deutschkron, Inge, 1979 (Folder 700: 11)
  - Deverall, Richard L. G., 1950-1957 (Folder 700: 12)
  - Dodd, Thomas J., 1961 (Folder 700: 13)
  - Dohrn, Klaus, 1953-1979 (Folder 700: 14)
  - Donahue, Thomas R., 1980-1987 (Box-folder 701: 1)
  - Donovan, William J., 1955 (Folder 701: 2)
  - Dorn, William Jennings Bryan, 1960 (Folder 701: 3)
  - Douglas, Paul H., 1949-1960 (Folder 701: 4)
  - Dozenberg, Nicholas, 1925-1931 (Folder 701: 5)
  - Driscoll, John J., 1978 (Folder 701: 6)
  - Dubinsky, David, 1952-1970 (Folder 701: 7)
  - Dulles, Allen W., 1954-1963 (Folder 701: 8)
  - Durbrow, Elbridge, 1977-1978 (Folder 701: 9)
  - East-West Round Table, 1982-1986 (Folder 701: 10)
  - Eban, Abba, 1964 (Folder 701: 11)
  - Economist, 1956-1977 (Folder 701: 12)
  - Eiran, Amos, 1974-1982 (Folder 701: 13)
  - Emmet, Christopher T., 1955 (Folder 701: 14)
  - Erler, Fritz, 1959 (Folder 701: 15)
  - Ernst, Robbi G. W., 1980-1981 (Folder 701: 16)
  - Euler, F., 1978 (Folder 701: 17)
  - Feuer, Lewis S., 1978-1982 (Folder 701: 18)
  - Fiester, Kenneth, 1955-1963 (Folder 701: 19)
  - Fisher, John M., 1961-1984 (Folder 701: 20)
  - Fitzgerald, F. Scott, 1935 (Folder 701: 21)
  - Flannery, Harry W., 1954 (Folder 701: 22)
  - Fontaine, André, 1977 (Folder 701: 23)
  - Force Ouvrière, 1973-1974 (Folder 701: 24)
  - Foreign Affairs Research Institute, 1977-1979 (Folder 701: 25)
  - France, Ministère de la Justice, 1959 (Folder 701: 26)
  - Freedoms Foundation, 1978-1982 (Folder 701: 27)
  - Frey, John P., 1942-1955 (Folder 701: 28)
  - Friedel, Samuel N., 1960 (Folder 701: 29)
  - Friedman, Robert I., 1987 (Folder 701: 30)
  - Front de Libération Nationale (Algeria), 1956-1963 (Folder 701: 31)
  - Fulbright, J. William, 1966 (Folder 701: 32)
  - Fulton, James G., 1955-1956 (Folder 701: 33)
  - Gaitskell, Hugh, 1958 (Folder 701: 34)
  - Gallois, Pierre M., 1963 (Folder 701: 35)
  - Gehlen, Reinhard, 1951-1977 (Folder 701: 36)
  - Geissler, Eva, undated (Folder 701: 37)
  - Geissler, Lu, 1925-1936 (Folder 701: 38)
  - General Motors Corporation, 1981 (Box-folder 702: 1)
  - George Meany Center for Labor Studies, 1979-1987 (Folder 702: 2)
  - Germany (West) Botschaft, United States, 1961-1974 (Folder 702: 3)
  - Gershman, Carl, 1978-1979 (Folder 702: 4)
  - Gilbert, Robert W., 1955 (Folder 702: 5)
  - Godson, Joseph, 1969 (Folder 702: 6)
  - Godson, Roy, 1975 (Folder 702: 7)
  - Goldberg, Arthur J., 1942-1961 (Folder 702: 8)
  - Goldberg, Harry, 1951-1967 (Folder 702: 9)
  - Good, Dale E., 1969-1985 (Folder 702: 10)
  - Gorman, Patrick E., 1974 (Folder 702: 11)
  - Gottschalk, Ellen, 1956 (Folder 702: 12)
  - Gould, Richard, 1977 (Folder 702: 13)
  - Gould, William B., 1982 (Folder 702: 14)
  - Graham, Philip L., 1955 (Folder 702: 15)
  - Gruenther, Alfred M., 1947-1956 (Folder 702: 16)
  - Guttenberg, Karl Theodor, Prinz zu, 1970-1971 (Folder 702: 17)
  - Habsburg, Otto von, 1962 (Folder 702: 18)
  - Hagnauer, Roger, 1955 (Folder 702: 19)
  - Haig, Alexander M., 1972-1982 (Folder 702: 20)
  - Hallstein, Walter, 1963 (Folder 702: 21)
  - Halpern, Seymour, 1960 (Folder 702: 22)
  - Hammarskjöld, Dag, 1956 (Folder 702: 23)
  - Hapgood, Powers, 1930 (Folder 702: 24)
  - Harriman, W. Averell, 1948-1963 (Folder 702: 25)
  - Haskins, Loyd A., 1965-1967 (Folder 702: 26)
  - Haya de la Torre, Victor, 1958 (Folder 702: 27)
  - Heine, Fritz
    - 1952-1962 (Folder 702: 28)
    - 1973-1979 (Folder 702: 29)
    - 1980-1981 (Folder 702: 30)
    - 1982-1984 (Folder 702: 31)
  - Hemphill, Robert W., 1960 (Box-folder 703: 1)
  - Henderson, Loy W., 1956 (Folder 703: 2)
  - Herling, John, 1955 (Folder 703: 3)
  - Hillenkoetter, R. H., 1955-1974 (Folder 703: 4)
  - Histadrut, 1963-1974 (Folder 703: 5)
  - Hochberg, Isadore, 1923-1926 (Folder 703: 6)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar, 1954-1956 (Folder 703: 7)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1955-1968 (Folder 703: 8)
  - Huyn, Hans, Graf, 1978-1982 (Folder 703: 9)
  - Ilan, Ben-Zion, 1964 (Folder 703: 10)
  - Independent Labor League of America, circa 1937 (Folder 703: 11)
  - Industrial College of the Armed Forces, 1976-1978 (Folder 703: 12)
  - Industrial Relations Research Association, 1956-1957 (Folder 703: 13)
  - Institute for Plural Societies, 1978 (Folder 703: 14)
  - International Confederation of Arab Trade-Unions, 1960-1961 (Folder 703: 15)
  - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions, 1961-1970 (Folder 703: 16)
  - International Conference in Honor of Andrei Sakharov, 1980-1981 (Folder 703: 17)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1947-1986 (Folder 703: 18)
  - International Rescue Committee, 1977 (Folder 703: 19)
  - Italian American Labor Council, 1977-1984 (Folder 703: 20)
  - Italy. Consolato Generale (New York, N.Y.), 1962 (Folder 703: 21)
  - Jackson, C. D., 1951 (Folder 703: 22)
  - Jackson, Henry M., 1971-1980 (Folder 703: 23)
  - Jakstas, Virginia, 1981 (Folder 703: 24)
  - Japanese Confederation of Labor, 1960-1969 (Folder 703: 25)
  - Javits, Jacob K., 1959-1972 (Folder 703: 26)
  - Jessup, John K., 1960 (Folder 703: 27)
  - Jewish Daily Forward, 1974-1977 (Folder 703: 28)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1962 (Folder 703: 29)
  - Judd, Walter H., 1955 (Folder 703: 30)
  - Kahn, Tom, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 704: 1)
  - Keat, Stephen K., 1981 (Folder 704: 2)
  - Keating, Kenneth B., 1960 (Folder 704: 3)
  - Kennedy, Robert F., 1963-1966 (Folder 704: 4)
  - Kersten, Otto, 1970-1974 (Folder 704: 5)
  - Kethly, Anna, 1959-1974 (Folder 704: 6)
  - Khan, Zafulla, 1961-1962 (Folder 704: 7)
  - Kiesinger, Kurt Georg, 1970 (Folder 704: 8)
  - Kirkland, Lane, 1978-1986 (Folder 704: 9)
  - Kirsch, Henry, 1967 (Folder 704: 10)
  - Kissinger, Henry A., 1958-1977 (Folder 704: 11)
  - Klehr, Harvey, 1980 (Folder 704: 12)
  - Knowland, William F., 1955 (Folder 704: 13)
  - Koevago, Joseph, 1957 (Folder 704: 14)
  - Kraemer, Fritz G. A., 1963-1986. (Folder 704: 15)
    Includes correspondence with others relating to dinners in honor of Kraemer.
  - Kreindler, Hannah, 1977-1979 (Folder 704: 16)
  - Kreisky, Bruno, 1961-1963 (Folder 704: 17)
  - Krock, Arthur, 1956 (Folder 704: 18)
  - Labin, Edouard, 1952 (Folder 704: 19)
  - La Dany, L., 1963 (Folder 704: 20)
  - Larkin, Anne, 1955 (Folder 704: 21)
  - Lash, Joseph P., 1979 (Folder 704: 22)
  - Leber, Georg, 1963-1982 (Folder 704: 23)
  - Lecoeur, Auguste, undated (Folder 704: 24)
  - Lee, Ernest S., 1956-1984 (Folder 704: 25)
  - Lewis, David Levering, 1979-1980 (Folder 704: 26)
  - Lewis, Flora, 1987 (Folder 704: 27)
  - Lewis, Marx, 1969 (Folder 704: 28)
  - Liebstein, A. Morris, 1959 (Folder 704: 29)
  - Limb, Ben C., 1952 (Folder 704: 30)
  - Lindblom, Olavi, 1956-1974 (Folder 704: 31)
  - Livingston, Sidney, 1970-1980 (Folder 704: 32)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1960-1964 (Folder 704: 33)
  - Loeb, William, 1959 (Folder 704: 34)
  - Lombardo, Ivan Matteo, 1961 (Folder 704: 35)
  - Lübke, Heinrich, 1964 (Folder 704: 36)
  - McDowell, Arthur G., 1955 (Folder 704: 37)
  - Magnuson, Don, 1960 (Folder 704: 38)
  - Makarios, Archbishop, 1964 (Folder 704: 39)
  - Maluleke, J. T., 1960-1961 (Folder 704: 40)
  - Mandel, Benjamin, 1954-1969 (Folder 704: 41)